Currently, this is our forecast list. It looks okay, but
it would be nice if we could show the degree
symbol for these temperature values. Using this notation is best
practice. It will help the translator know how to reorder the
text and the parameters so that it fits the local
language. Now let's look at how we can use this
method to format temperatures within our app. Within the string.xml
file, we declared the format temperature string resource. We use xliff
tag to denote that this is where the decimal temperature
value will go. This is followed by the unit code
character for the degrees symbol. In the utility class, in
the format temperature method, we can use this string resource. Remember
that, in this method, we take in a temperature and
a user's preference for metric or imperial. Then, we return
the converted temperature. We're going to modify this method so that
it also returns the formatted string with a degrees symbol after
the value. In order to do this. We need to past
in a context. From the context we can get access to the
string resource ID that we declared earlier. Then we passed in any
additional parameters for that string template. In this case we only have
one parameters so we pass in the temperature value. Then this
fully formatted string gets returned to the caller. This method is used
in the forecast list, as well in the detail page. So we
also had to update the code there so that it would compile
with this new parameter. And this is what the app looks like after
the change. Go ahead and make the change in your code to add a
string resource for displaying temperature in
degrees. Check this box when you're done.
And remember, use this notation going forward
for when you need to format strings